hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski and if you haven't
listened to this podcast before i help
coaches trainers authors and mentors
scale their businesses find their niche
and know exactly what they need to do to
get more clients
fast if you want to make six figures
seven figures or even go to eight
figures i'd love to help you do so we
actually have events that we're running
every other week that you can check out
over on my social media to help you for
free get the step by step of what it
takes to start to get more clients in
your business now i have the honor of
having a mentor here his name is jim
landers and he helps
low-volume photographers meaning they're
they're not like
doing
um a ton of photography they do more
high-end high-priced
photo shoots low-volume photographers
get clients as well as get better at
their craft and so jim welcome to the
podcast how are you doing today thank
you jeremiah i'm doing great thank you
for having me on i i'm excited when you
when you said yes to being on here i
know we had a great conversation a few
months back and and i was like you know
i think
you have some value that you could bring
to the to the listeners on here to be a
great conversation so
tell me a little bit about what got you
into
coaching a lot of the people who listen
to this podcast they're like
man i want to i want to get into
coaching or training but how do i find
my niche how do i find my
my lane of like what i'm good at and so
what got you into it well
um i suppose that's a long story but i'm
not going to tell you the long version
but i've been interested in photography
since i was a kid i was i was six years
old um and
of course then it was just a thought
it's just an idea
but in in high school i took classes and
then in college i actually went and got
a degree in photography i have a
four-year degree in photography that i
got many years ago i'm not going to say
exactly when but
at that point i really you know felt
like i
that i knew what i was doing that i had
a great four-year education that i had
wonderful teachers because i did
but then reality hits
and you struggle at the beginning trying
to get your business photography
business to work and you start noticing
those around you the 33 students that i
graduated with i'm one of 33 started
disappearing
falling out not doing photography
anymore
and within five years
i couldn't find a single one left doing
it i think i was the only one within
five years of the program ending
and so i got to that that point where
i'm thinking
you know it took me a while i'm a slow
learner jeremiah i i it took me a while
to get to this point but
people are if they're being honest with
themselves
we learn it takes us way longer than we
want to yes uh man you'd think i would
have figured this out pretty quickly but
i still didn't my eyes still weren't
open to what's going on here but now
looking back at it with you know with a
different point of view you know
hindsight is 20 20 we all have heard
that one
i look back at my my um
education my formal education as being
very good
but i realize now not one of my teachers
and i actually knew it then
but it didn't i guess it never crossed
my mind
i was being trained by someone who had
never done what i was what they were
training me to do wow not one of my
teachers i had seven photography
teachers in college not one of them had
been a
photographer not as an income source now
all of them you know could press the
easy button and and uh create beautiful
photographs but that's a totally
different thing than making an income to
pay for your mortgage and put food on
the table it's a totally different thing
i and so um
again it took me a while but at some
point i started realizing
this is
this is an area i can help you you know
you your mom probably told you this or
somebody that um
if you're if in your mind you're
thinking somebody needs to do this
that's your flag that's going up saying
it's you who needs to do this and so at
some point i started realizing oh
yeah okay it's me i'm the one who's
supposed to stand up and
help other other photographers make this
work and so about 2009 i started writing
on the business side now it took a while
before i started presenting what i wrote
because you know i it wasn't
i didn't think it was very good it
probably was pretty good but
i i don't know i just didn't feel like
it and so um i had those classes
available and i taught them you know as
a one-on-one just private coaching
and but i started expanding that
probably by 2015 so it took me about
five years um to where he really got
serious about that business side and
started really expanding it beyond just
a one-on-one and started doing group uh
coaching with it
uh and had been doing that in one form
or another since then
i want to point out a few of the things
that you said here and pause here and
kind of expand upon them i think you
just tapped into two really key parts
that will help
people that want to get into coaching is
a one
is
take a look at things that you've
learned
that quote unquote came
easy to you that you enjoy
that other people who learn the same
stuff didn't quite get it at the same
level
and those things could be
good for you to
at least start with making a niche in
you know i have a number of people uh
one of my clients rick pino he does
uh worship songwriting and publishing
classes but he has a number of students
that are like hey i want to teach this
as well and they actually can teach the
the recording side of things better than
other people they can teach the nuanced
sides of it and so some of you take a
look at what you have
learned yourself
that maybe other people have struggled
with
that came a little bit easier to you or
that you said hey i need to learn more
and you really had a passion for
learning more of that's a good hint of
what you can coach and the other one is
like you just said jim um
if
if nobody else is doing it and you're
saying you know i wish there was
somebody that's doing that that might be
a good indicator of a niche that you
could go into that's called a blue ocean
strategy where it's like
blue ocean instead of red ocean
everybody's doing this versus you could
actually become the category king
one of the only people that's doing it
and and you don't have to work as hard
would you do that so
that's awesome tell me a little bit
about when you're coaching
um photographers on how to get clients
what's the number one thing
that
you notice your students
struggle with
that you help them with what's one of
the biggest kind of problems and i
always talk about this in your marketing
you want to lead with problem and then
solution what would say be one of those
problems that like your students
struggle with and how do you help them
work through those well there's
certainly a lot of them but probably the
number one is getting new clients or
getting clients that are willing to pay
what they're charging and so
so getting the ideal client is probably
the number one uh concern
or or problem that they're experiencing
yeah
and so what what stops people from
getting people to pay them
what they're charging what do you find
is like that biggest thing and i know
you mentioned a lot of stuff even
even mentally
if we look at photography it's an art
form and so art coaching is a unique
niche that even not a lot of people are
in a lot of people like either in
personal development business coaching
health coaching
uh finances things like that but art
coaching is unique because
um
we almost think of art and sales as
almost like they're like water and oil
oh that's so true and yeah how do you
navigate that and help people because if
instead of being a
starving artist
a starving photographer it's possible to
be a thriving photographer and make a
full-time living and so what are some of
those areas that you help them work
through and i think some of those areas
we have we actually have a lot of
creatives who listen to this podcast and
are doing creative art coaching and i
think they could learn from that from
you oh man um
it's in some circles considered a virtue
to not make money with your art
all right it's insane uh and uh
there's a school that's not far from
where you are it's not in in not in your
city but it's it's not far from there
where there are some fantastic teachers
on the photography side
but they are
anti-business and if you even talk about
doing it a for profit outside of
galleries they're good with galleries um
the galleries are often not very
profitable
um but uh they will
they'll give you a hard time in class
they'll tell you that you're a sellout
they'll make it it's they'll make it
very difficult for you to actually make
a living it's like they're training you
to be a starving artist and if you're
not a starving artist you're selling out
you're not being you're not doing being
true to your art uh it's you you ha you
are less than and this is how they're
teaching it and i am amazed that they
get away with this um partially because
i think it should be illegal to do that
because when a parent pays for for their
kids education to go through their
education they're expecting that student
to be independent at some point after
they finish that program they're
expecting them to be able to create an
income source for themselves as a result
and those students get out of that
program
not only with not an income source but
with an anti-feeling against making
money with their articles
and we see that a lot in in culture that
almost like you know making money is bad
written people are evil if they're
making money they must be doing
something evil
you're you're
you're less than and art is you're right
it's one of the number one areas as if
your art is less than because it's
making money and in demand
um
that's a whole other like that's crazy
stuff it's um now those who come to me
or don't have that that feeling but they
may have had it at one point in their
lives and it definitely
could have influenced them but i've had
people who have it
yeah oh yes they absolutely are so it is
influencing them even if they they feel
like it's not correct they're still
being influenced by you're right
i've had a handful of interns from those
from that school and that's the only
reason i know about their their program
doing that is uh because i've had i
believe a total of five that i've talked
to and three of them have been interns
but each one of them have shared the
same story without me
asking about it do you have teachers
that do this i don't ask the questions
like that because i actually want to get
an honest answer and even though they
were from different years two of them
were from the the same year they were
contemporary but um the rest of them
were not they wouldn't have known each
other they all told me the same story so
therefore that's just their culture
that's just what they believe in and
my school wasn't like that they were not
anti-making money
but they also
didn't teach the business side at all in
fact i remember twice the subject came
up um i didn't ask it because i was
oblivious
um go figure i i guess i was into well
it doesn't matter what i was into
the the um
i heard i remember two times someone
asking about business and um and i don't
remember exactly what their questions
were but i remember the answers from
these two different teachers one said i
won't be on the test don't worry about
it
and the other one said you don't
actually need that until after you
graduate
okay wow
are you not the person who's supposed to
prepare me for what happens after i
graduate yeah
you're you're passionate about this i
can tell and just helping people
get clients it's so important to do that
i want to just it's funny my background
i i was super into photography when i
was
oh really 12 years old
cool but then i shifted so i just a
bunch of stop-motion photography and
then i realized oh there's these cameras
that i don't have to click it they're
called video cameras
so i got into
i got into video it was kind of my thing
and storytelling and and and to this day
i utilize storytelling and video in all
of my marketing um i'm the reason i'm
kind of make so much video content is
because i
have been using a camera and being in
front of it and talking in front of one
since i was a teenager um but what i
found was is that it wasn't uh i ended
up doing video for a sales training
company uh
dannyjohnson.com was the name of it and
they're they're actually located up in
kerrville texas
um so they're and i actually moved to
tech that's how i moved to texas the
first time as i was working for them out
in california they moved to kerrville
and i was making their videos together
but what i realized was okay
video isn't going to make me rich
working for somebody else i need to
learn sales and i need to learn how to
get clients and i need to learn how to
take what i have a passion for which
really is
i've i found a a new passion
for helping uh people that have a lot of
impact like coaches trainers mentors the
person i was working for danny johnson
she was a coach and a trainer so my
first job was working on videos i ended
up in that company helping them with a
lot of their sales messaging and a lot
of their marketing as well and that's
how i ended up transitioning into what i
do uh today is is is through that and
because i realized okay you need to
understand sales
to to actually fund your vision i still
have a dream to this day to develop
video games and movies and more from
like a pre executive producer standpoint
um you know find people with great ideas
and help fund their ideas that's gonna
take a lot of money for me to do that
and so sales is the number one way for
me to to get to that level how do you
handle i'm saying this for a reason when
somebody
is is a photographer and they've had all
this training and they're indoctrinated
with all this information
or maybe they're just around it
and and they come to you
how do you help them
break through what they're being told
and the messaging that they're being
told all the time to understand what
they need to do to start to get clients
and what is the shift that happens in a
lot of them
well that's a good question if they're
coming to me it's because
they are
they're struggling or they uh
so and those that are in that category
um would uh have already had in their
mind they want to do portrait
photography
um
and so they would be coming even though
they had that uh that philosophy they'd
be coming to me um it reminds me of a um
a guy that reached out to me
it was probably at the beginning of this
year
and uh he said
i don't even know why i'm calling you i
know i'm calling you but
i i i don't like you
i don't like anything about you i i am
offended by every single post you make
but i am
i'm going to set that aside for just a
moment because i've been struggling for
years
and i think i can learn something from
you
wow and i i said
i i i i said let's get our calendar out
i want to take you to lunch
yeah yeah so i took him to lunch and we
and we talked and by the end of that
lunch he said
i i don't know why i don't like you i
don't know why i didn't like you i i
it's it doesn't make any sense to me i i
had this preconceived
no i'm now putting my own words because
i this isn't exactly how he said it but
this was the gist i i he effectively
said
i had a preconceived idea
i thoroughly believed it
to the point where i wouldn't have any
reason to to research it
and i moved on with life with that
preconceived idea even though it was
wrong um and and now he's a coaching
client so
it totally turned around from someone
who is
bothered and totally bothered and
offended by my posts
to someone who is taking my advice what
were some of the things that he was like
offended by and that he kind of came
around to i think like
so so like specifics
well he he said everything so i didn't
he didn't bring up anything in in
specifically but he literally said
everything in fact that that part he he
wrote because he started off his
the the reaching out that he did to me
was and i i
i think i implied that it was a phone
call it was a messenger facebook
messenger message uh and he he wrote
that
but that's when i responded by saying
let's let's uh
let's go have lunch and i do that i i
take a photographer to lunch uh every
once a week uh that particular week it
was two because because
i i had already taken someone to lunch
that week um but yeah it's pretty pretty
amazing how things change and and now i
am seeing a lot of
positive action in his uh you know from
coming from him whereas before it seemed
like he was just upset about things and
everything seemed to upset him uh and
make him cranky and angry
and there's
there's no positive when you're pouring
negative
into your tank
so he's he he was pouring negative into
his tank thinking that that was that was
right and it was it was correct for him
and i'm not saying he doesn't do it at
all anymore i'm just saying there's a
lot more positive coming from him right
totally that's amazing and
i'll i'll ask you this i
some of your messaging so like for
instance a lot of my coaches and
trainers and mentors
they are like you know
they they naturally
have a bent towards people pleasing
yeah and a bent towards they don't want
to upset anybody they don't want to
offend anybody but what's amazing is
just from your story that you just
shared there this person who was
offended by what you said
didn't like you actually came around
became a client and became one of your
biggest fans
and so like how does that work and how
does somebody get to that place how did
you get to that place where like
hey you weren't reactive or judgmental
of him saying that i think that that's a
that's a powerful testament to what kind
of man coach and mentor you are that you
weren't immediately like well screw you
then dude
and i've i've struggled with that
attitude when people like come to me and
say that
i've got a lot better at it but like i'm
like okay the reason they're saying this
has to do with them not me
and so what is that that is tough
you're right because that we
we all have feelings yeah and
and we are absolutely influenced and
affected by those feelings so no matter
how positive a person we are we think we
are and we're we're affected by those
those negative feelings um
and and they initially i think that it's
out of our control i think that it just
boom we have a reaction but our
subsequent actions are
completely and totally our own i mean if
if i was if i was angry with someone
and uh you know
there was maybe a situation between me
and another person we were working
together or uh maybe it's a spouse maybe
it's a friend whatever but um you have
words uh if if that person reacts to you
then with anger in return it makes sense
why someone would do that but if someone
if someone were angry with me and
sharing me their story if
i i want to think about it in a slightly
different way
if they were speaking to me in a
different language a language i don't
know i don't have any relationship to
whatsoever they are getting angry with
me in that language
i don't know what it is they're saying
i might even think it sounds funny and
and laugh about it so therefore it isn't
their words
it isn't it isn't them that's causing me
a problem it's internal it's me it's the
words it's it's me using those words
inside of me and getting get getting
upset about it because if they if they'd
if
that same individual getting upset with
me in a different language i would not
have had that reaction
wow it was because of how i received it
that i had that reaction
that's powerful
so i i don't know that doesn't um i mean
that's oh that's that's one way to look
at it but reality is we have our initial
reactions and we get angry and it makes
us it clouds
a judgement at that point
what i've learned um just in my own
journey
as as somebody i i
i've been somebody who over the years
and there's people that have known me
for years they followed me they remember
when i was this way they've seen it
where like somebody could say something
to me in just the right way and i would
verbally like react and kind of go crazy
um and and almost like lose self-control
in that and it's and i and i actually
vulnerably and confidently share that
about how i used to be
because i've had to learn exactly what
you said it wasn't what they said it was
what was inside of me the meaning that i
applied to it and and usually that
meaning for me came up based off of some
situation whether it be my childhood
teenage years past interactions with
with with people like those people um
you know
men that remind me of guys at church
when i was growing up that were
looking back it was in a very healthy
situation just things like that like
whatever it is people they were in
school and they were bullied and so like
our reaction reminds us of these of
these situations and we apply meaning
that isn't even there to somebody else
who they're they're applying meaning
themselves to it
and so when we can when we can learn
that internal game
i think that's really important and and
to learn um to learn self-control one of
my favorite things as well as um
i love reading at least once a month uh
listening through usually on youtube
like a summary of the meditations of
marcus aurelius yeah have you ever have
you ever gone through those no really
cool i'm curious yeah there's there's
like 30 minute videos on youtube about
it and you know who marcus israelis was
though yeah yeah so he was the roman
emperor roman that went to egypt and was
with cleopatra
and he um
he wrote down
his journal
and they're called the meditations of
marcus aurelius and it's been translated
over the years
around stoic philosophy and the one of
the biggest things is about not
letting other people's opinions
knock us off track
um while still being humble
and and being able to operate how does a
roman emperor operate in that way you
have thousands of people in your empire
that hate you and so he literally talks
about that and it's so weird it's from
2000 years ago and yet it feels like
you're reading
a personal development book written last
year
about what we're going through as
business owners
from this guy and so i it's some of the
greatest um
writings on this topic it kind of when i
read it it snaps me like right into
order as far as like not
really worrying as much about what
people think
i had somebody about a year ago i was
telling them about the meditations of
marcus aurelius
and they immediately reacted and said
that's some of the worst teaching out
there and it will ruin you and ruin all
your relationships and it's funny
i
i took to heart what he said and i
erased a lot of that from my mind and as
soon as i picked it back up about three
months ago i was like no this is i let
that other person's opinion actually
dictate that to me
and literally shape my brain for like
two years off of what one person said
that wasn't even true based off of what
they thought so it's amazing how
we try to
be liked by other people and we change
the way that we think and we do certain
things and that comes right into our
businesses
to where
if you're a coach if you're a trainer if
you're a photographer if you're an
artist
you don't put yourself out there you
don't
get clients because we're afraid of how
people will react to us the fear of the
unknown
do you find that a lot of photographers
and artists are afraid of they're not
sure if people are going to pay them so
they're afraid to actually ask to be
paid
that's a good a very good question um
they
they okay we humans come with
preconceived ideas we just do uh and one
of those is on that sales side that they
don't feel like um they have a negative
interpretation of what a sales person is
they're saying they're saying the slick
they're thinking the slick sales person
the person who has the quick one-liners
who's trying to persuade you to buy
something that you don't need you don't
want and you can't afford and so they've
got that preconceived idea in their head
sales is bad
which is insane because sales is the
ultimate in helping another person right
it's helping someone else get what it is
that they want or need that's what sales
is
but man we artists i don't know i'm sure
it's just a human thing but i we
creatives and which is how i generally
refer to us yeah we create his head this
negative connotation of sales and so
when we do it we start
i don't know we we judge ourselves and
and we are concerned about how other
people think and uh we want people to be
able to to we we feel like we're
supposed to help people afford it um but
in my opinion
getting into their finances unless
that's your job
is rude
yeah it's not up to me to decide what
they value
i
my job is to make sure i value me and
what i care about enough to charge an
amount that causes me to be able to
reach my goals and causes my family to
be able to to reach whatever it is that
we want to to reach and whatever that
cost is that's the that's what i have to
charge my clients in order to reach that
goal now what someone else values is
theirs it is
totally theirs it's mean of me it's rude
of me to jump in and say i need to make
it more affordable for you because you
can't afford it how rude
you you just hit something i've never
heard somebody articulate it that way
before and that's honestly some of the
best
uh
sales content in like a minute i'm gonna
i might have to clip that
uh i i'll send you the recording of this
podcast too you can clip it for some of
your content for your people honestly
that was like the one of the best
one-liners about sales i've ever heard
um because it's true like who is who are
we to say oh they can't afford it yeah
who are we to say that they can't um and
and and i think i think offering like
certain financing and stuff there's
different things that we can do that for
sure to help people um but not devaluing
ourselves as long as we're not doing it
to devalue ourselves that's so important
um my mind is just actually kind of
blown by by what you said
is
i've always heard like we if we know we
can help somebody we have a moral
obligation to to
offer them that help but we have what we
need to charge for it instead of saying
i'm going to do it for free
and sometimes somebody needs to pay for
it to actually get it i do a lot of like
free events and podcasts and stuff and
and
i was wanting in the beginning of this
business so i had built
a couple of eight-figure coaching
businesses before but then i was like
when i went off on my own i was like you
know what i want to help as many people
and i'm going to just give everything
away for free
um and i found that that
95 of people that were listening to my
free content weren't doing anything with
it
and only and the ones that were actually
making money working with me were paying
me a lot of money to work with me
and so i realized i'm actually doing a
disservice to the people that i'm
coaching by doing that
by giving away so much for free i was
doing like
hour-long phone calls i did them with
450 people
uh in a year
um now what's cool is i got a lot of
data about my target customer i've used
that and that's helped me pivot my
business into the right niche which is
awesome
um but you can do that a lot faster i'm
running a five-day event right now to
help people build their own six-figure
coaching business when somebody joins
that event the first question that's
asked is
um actually let me see what the what the
what the question is
what is your number one problem that
keeps you up at night from building a
coaching business
and what would you love to learn in
these five days
and so i actually have i'm
on my computer right here
over
19 pages of 200 people's responses to
those two questions that i've gathered
in the last 48 hours nice now here's
what's crazy about that the answers to
those questions
identified a lane of content that i
haven't been addressing in over four
years
this podcast right here now is
addressing that lane of content and so i
immediately have pivoted and adjusted
all of my content to what people
actually want i didn't have to hop on
450 calls with people to do that it took
48 hours of just getting people into a
facebook group for an event to do that
and so i use that as a way to build
trust with people and to do market
research and then we adjust our
messaging uh based off of that so that
we're finally finding the lane of people
and the exact words what i'll use is
i'll use a tool like jasper ai i love
jasper ai i talk about it i'll take the
answers from these people and i'll
filter it through jasper and then jasper
will actually generate the offer copy
for my offers and generate titles for my
content and my podcast episodes that's
fantastic all using ai in less than like
it take and that maybe takes me like a
half hour to do
and so
a lot of people i think coaches trainers
mentors you don't have to work as hard
to make money
i think a lot of times we think that we
need to work more hours to make money
that we need to make more hours do you
find that's the case with the people
that you work with that they think to
make more money means more hours of work
and is that true
maybe in the beginning but not long term
yeah um
it's it's interesting because with
uh you definitely have all types who who
i who i get to i i get the privilege of
working with and uh some of them are
very much on the i only want to do this
a certain number of hours per week maybe
maybe it's moms who want to do it while
their kids are in school and so they
have between 9 30 and 3 o'clock to be
able to do their business um and and uh
but that's not the norm that there's a
handful of those and i i find them
fascinating i just think they're yeah
how how do you how do you make that work
and it's fantastic that you that you are
making that work um
and it's it's fun helping them um but
that's that's a smaller percentage so
the the majority even though they they
may have kids in school um are
are working it like a regular job but
they're doing it in the evenings
sometimes after the kids have gone to
bed when they're doing their uh i call
artwork retouching
and uh organizing of their images and
it's amazing for a photographer the
amount of time that's invested that is
unseen it's usually about a 10 to a 20
to one ratio and so if you see your
photographer for an hour i guarantee you
they're putting in 10 hours worth of
work in order to make that one hour look
good in order to make it happen because
there's just a massive amount of stuff
that goes into it and photography is one
of those interesting
uh
things that you could learn that you'll
never learn all there is to know it's
not possible if you if someone has an
interest and they stopped doing
everything and made photography
education just learning photography
their only thing they did they could
study
for the rest of their life right still
not learn all there is to know there's
just too much to do with sales and
marketing too yeah
any industry any niche i i've been
exploring
uh storytelling how to write novels and
doing that i've i've been reading
through like 20 different novels just to
get the art form of how to tell us a
story like a fiction story and i'm like
barely scratching the surface of like
okay how does how does fiction actually
work that's so true you can always learn
that but when it comes to implementing
when it comes to taking action um to get
more clients to get more people to pay
you money and to increase your income
um does that always take more hours or
what does that take
no you're right about it in the
beginning it you do need to to uh think
this through
and do not do this alone it's a waste of
time to do this alone
get a coach get visit with someone who's
doing this before and and i don't know
about other industries but in in
photography 90
of all photographers have a price that's
so low they don't even give themselves
potential to have an income and about 60
of them don't even know it they're
totally oblivious to it they're thinking
i i i i just i charge 200
for uh and i i don't charge this i'm i'm
saying someone else yeah um 200 for a
session i i can pretty much do that i it
depends there are exceptions but for the
most part i can mathematically prove
you're one of the ones going out of
business 200 is not going to cause you
to make it happen it's just not yeah
so why they need to charge to actually
be in business like everyone's everyone
of course is different because they they
do different things and they do require
different amounts of time
but uh uh
you know
it acts i mean we could just pull out a
calculator and and figure it out um you
know if someone wants this as their
full-time job versus someone who just
wants it uh as a part-time
now everything's costing you it is yeah
no kidding throw that stuff in um but if
someone wants to do it as a
as a full-time job i start off with the
end result by by asking what do they
want out of this life what what kind of
variables are important to them and i
have a um i've got something that and i
guess i have it handy enough where i
could just show you uh i've got this
life goals chart and and they just write
down what it is that's important to them
so these are the 11 categories uh that i
find important um and if they do too
they put something in there whatever's
important to them and then put an amount
to it and and then uh timeline it i want
them to just to define for themselves
when they want these things so that they
know how much money they're going to
need in order to make it happen and when
they're going to need that money because
that's the only way your pricing should
be done you shouldn't base your pricing
on what other photographers are charging
it's irrelevant to what others are
charging because if you're charging what
they charge but it doesn't cause you to
reach your goal
then what what good is it it's
ridiculous
yes you have to do the things that cause
you to reach your goals you cannot do
this on your own you can't yeah you can
but it'll take you a decade to two
decades in order to get to that point
and you really have that kind of time
you don't you don't yeah you don't
you need to work with somebody you need
a coach you you need someone and i
mentioned earlier about 90 of
photographers have a price that's so low
that you're not going that they don't
make a profit so how do you know that
you're going to the right person for
advice
ninety percent of the 90
chance you go into the wrong person for
advice and so
if you go to other photographers
websites and check out what they're
doing
which you should i mean that's a
curiosity thing you're curious as to
what they do but just like their words
shouldn't influence you
neither should their price list
if they have a marketing
system that's working success leaves
clues i think you told me that
the success leaves clues so therefore
yeah
learn from it but don't be influenced by
their pricing because their pricing is
theirs and if they've done it right it's
based off of their wants their dreams
their goals and their loved ones um and
yours should be also it should have
nothing to do with theirs uh so we
define you know what is it that i need
to to make in the long run and then
break that down into how much do i need
all the way down to how much do i need
to make this year or how much do i need
to make next year and how do i how do i
form a path
to get there
i want to say what you just shared here
that right there um i'm probably gonna
even borrow a little bit of that with
some of my group coaching and even in my
building a six-figure coaching thing is
i i tell people to imagine like making a
certain income level but i think they
also need to get real with their goals
do you find a lot of people actually
have never thought about their goals
before everybody says that
yeah really it's rare it's rare that i
come across someone who has done
anything even slightly in that direction
interesting i've been i've been in this
space
my mind is actually i'm learning
something right now
i've i've been so indoctrinated with
goals goals goals my whole life that i
just assumed everybody else was
and so i right there i i'm gonna start
talking more about goals in the
beginning with people when they find
their niche what their pricing is and
all that is really what are your goals
and what i love to do is is i love to
help people build a
six-figure income seven-figure coaching
income
even an eight-figure income and i've
seen this my my mom is a great example
of this because this is what i grew up
around eight figure coaching business
working five hours a week because that's
the life that she's wanted
and doing so without a bunch of
employees either
and so how do you got to price stuff to
do that how do you got to structure
things to be able to do that and so
that's a lot of the model that i help
people with is you know if you wanna if
you wanna work only five to ten hours a
week now in the beginning you're gonna
have to grind it out you might have to
work some
late nights and do that but once the
system starts kicking in
i usually tell people in the coaching
business once you're making over about
30 000 consistently a month you can
automate most of the stuff
and it's very easy to get to that level
once you figure out your messaging um
and so that's powerful though about the
goals i think
those that are listening to this right
now
go back and maybe even can you show that
screen where what those goals are i'd
love even people to pause the podcast
episode if they're watching the video
version of this just to pause it on this
and
kind of list those if you're listening
it says what are your health goals what
are your travel goals what about
contribution and charity
uh hobbies play and rest um
social goals friends
uh relationships family career financial
home car stuff
what's the uh does that say oh mental
emotional and spiritual goals and so
think about those
um you can you can put that back down
now
think about those in your own life is
and get real with those
you have to create the life and the
person that you want to be first and
start with the end in mind i think
that's so important a lot of my early
podcast episodes talked about that more
than anything
um if people go back through some of the
early podcasts i talked about your
purpose and finding a business that fits
your purpose and i really broke a lot of
that down i haven't touched on that in a
long time though because i focus more on
the marketing side of things but i think
that's important to not skip over so
just thank you for bringing that here
uh jim and anybody who's listening to
this podcast is going to get a lot of
value out of that
any any other closing thoughts that you
want to share just for people that are
they they want to
coach they want to serve people they
want to have an impact and ultimately
make a full-time income doing so any
other advice that you give them before
we close here
yeah
and i'm going to
to read this
because i don't want to
skip anything
yeah but uh
let's see
there's there's three things
actually i add more to it but there's uh
let's do four there's four steps
to reaching your goals
in in my opinion
one is determine your destination that's
the
life goals that i'm talking about
uh the second is to plan
your path
the third
get on that path with passion
dedication
and an appropriate amount of
stubbornness
and number four
adjust as needed
because it's not set in stone and things
change
that's good
i think a lot of people are afraid to
adjust as needed too because they're
like does that make me
a failure
does that make me a failure that i
adjusted as needed
that make sure you ask people that
question
uh my my mom is a great example of this
and and rick pino two two great examples
of this adjust as needed in their
coaching businesses
so my mom was teaching social media and
facebook ads and a lot of that and
she
she pivoted into teaching the stock
market and increased her income by 500
so she adjusted to a different niche
that she actually just learned two years
ago but she's gotten really good at
because she literally became obsessed
with and learned everything and
dedicated every hour of her day to and
and and
her coaching income 5x and she's done
pouring that into the stock market and
growing that with
like that it's it's amazing if anybody
wants to trade stocks like she's she's
probably one of the one of the maverick
like most easy to understand people
because she's not super technical she's
just like anybody else um and she breaks
it down in a very easy way now rick pino
his was interesting he started as his
coaching was
mostly just spirituality coaching
christian
uh bible teaching around worship
and so it had nothing to do with like
music industry and he actually said i
don't want to do anything with music
industry i just want to help people with
the bible aspect of it and he
but but everybody was asking him like
hey like i want to learn how to write
songs and as soon as he pivoted and
finally was like you know what like okay
i've done this for four years and this
is what he said he said there's like six
or seven other people now that are
teaching worship bible teaching and
they're teaching it as good as i am so i
feel good about now pivoting into
helping people write songs because i
helped start
people teaching this stuff and
influenced a lot of people to teach it
themselves that's one thing as a coach
is that you'll find my mom found the
same thing she was one of the first
people teaching social media now
everybody is teaching social media so
she's like what more can i teach let me
find something else she's found that
there's a lot of misinformation in the
stock market and teaching and so she's
changing that that industry as well and
so that's what happened with rick when
he pivoted instantly eight figures it
went right up to the eight-figure level
by giving people what they wanted even
though it went against what he wanted to
give people it was listening to people
and he still includes a ton of the
spirituality training that he wants to
into that because he feels it's
foundational
but people are more willing to pay more
money because it's more it's more
business related versus just let's let's
study the bible together type of a thing
at that level he was giving stuff away
for like a dollar
you know here's it's a dollar it's 27
bucks for like the whole thing and now
it's like to even work with him on the
songwriting level it's twelve thousand
five hundred dollars minimum and that
was what was able to take him to that
eight figure level
is by figuring that out and and working
on the messaging and so hey don't be
afraid to charge what you're worth
don't be afraid to pivot and adjust your
niche as you learn new information and
say hey maybe okay this group of people
is going to make me more money i did
this in this business my own business i
forexed our income
in my coaching business
since january that's why i'm pivoting
only to helping coaches mentors trainers
and authors
nice um which is interesting everybody
that i've helped over the last 19 years
the ones that i've actually gotten
results for were in that lane but i was
like i want to help everybody make money
on the internet
and so i had a lot of confused and
unfortunately a few disappointed people
who came to me for e-commerce and
affiliate marketing and network
marketing and and and i'm not an expert
in those fields uh but the ones who came
to me for the coaching niche they
started to grow grow and get the
positive results i said okay i need to
just focus on this niche of people
um and i'm even finding more and more
where i need to niche down even more i'm
still testing a few things out
and that's how you do it you look at the
data and you do pattern recognition okay
what is the pattern across the people
who are coming to me
what is the specific pattern of
the ones that are most successful
and the ones that have paid me the most
money
and when there's a specific pattern
where those two things are in mind
now the only way you're going to find
that data is by actually putting your
stuff out there if you've never put
anything out there you have no way of
identifying that data you can observe
other people's businesses but you don't
have it for your own data once you've
done that for your own business you can
really identify what is it going to take
to easily create a six figure income on
autopilot i just launched my group
coaching program uh and it's already a
six-figure recurring income source for
me
uh over over eight thousand three
hundred and thirty three dollars a month
coming in in the first two weeks of
launching it because i identified
exactly what the niche was
exactly what people want and now i want
to grow it i'm going to 10x that to
where it's a seven figure recurring
income source in the next
six to 12 months
and that's what i think any coach or
trainer can do
but it takes
being willing to adjust being willing to
pivot being willing to
be a little bit uncomfortable
maybe have uncomfortable conversations
with people
being willing to have haters instead of
trying to make everybody happy
and i think that's what's going to help
take people to the level that they need
to be financially
yeah do you have any thoughts on that
makes total sense
that's awesome i couldn't say it any
better so
you're awesome jim i appreciate you
being here i think i think uh we might
have to have you back too in a couple of
months you just you have so many like
pearls of wisdom to share with people
that like and that's what i love when
somebody's like man like how long have
you been doing this for
i i've been teaching since 97 but the
business side since 2009 yeah
that's a long time in this industry
that's a long time it really is and and
you've learned a lot of stuff that like
i'm telling you you know you know stuff
that as like the top one percent know
about what it takes and and so i
appreciate the value that you're
bringing here this is incredible thank
you so much for just your time today and
i think this is really going to bless
the podcast listeners well i i
appreciate you sharing that jeremiah and
i i i
feel honored to have been asked to uh to
be on your show
and and uh
to spend time with you and and hear your
words of wisdom because you you have a
lot to share and i've i've learned a lot
from from you and and you know watching
the the things that you're doing and
being part of of what you do and so i i
am blessed to to know you and and i i
value that relationship well thank you
for that where can people find you
online
landersphotoschool.com
okay landersphotoschool.com
and then what's the one that's like you
have
portrait profits what's this yes uh
portrait prophets and you can go to
portraitprofits.com too but um i have a
a weekly show that i do for for
photographers uh and it's on the
business side it's also a little on the
philosophy side yeah because one of our
most recent ones was called people
pleasers that was probably about two
three weeks ago that's pretty recent i
think a lot of the listeners of this
podcast even if you're not a
photographer but you're in art in the
art space specifically could really
benefit from even just plugging in and
and maybe you could learn photography
from jim and and find a new love and a
new art that you never knew that you had
inside of you
i'd encourage anybody to do that
um so that that's what facebook.com
forward slash portrait profits awesome
that's great
well thank you for being here and listen
those of you that are listening to this
podcast if this has helped you in any
way make sure that you share it don't
keep this information to yourself that's
the biggest thing that i'd ask you this
podcast is free
and we're giving you like high level
training in this like you what you just
got out of this one episode people pay a
lot of money for
and and
and because it's free not a lot of
people apply it because it's like oh
it's free but like those that do apply
it if you take even just one nugget away
from this your business could explode in
the next month and so share this with
others
and and think about jumping into one of
the live events that i'm doing if you're
a coach if you're a trainer and you want
to know how do i grow my business to six
or seven figures as well as the client
growth accelerator where i get to work
with you in a group coaching setting to
help you grow your business and get more
clients alright everybody grow your life
and we'll talk soon have a good one